# Matthew Zuckman

I'm a passionate design leader—transforming insight and opportunity into compelling experiences. I shift design cultures and build empowered teams. I develop product and marketing systems that work across platforms, screens, and customers. And I've got the track record to prove it.

# Employment History

## **Director of Design for Viator**

2016-present

- Led the transition of the designers, marketers, researchers, and coders into an agile environment, working effectively to develop practices for rigor, communication, and quality.
- Strategized across executives to plan and execute a unified direction for B2B, B2C businesses and customers.
- Initiated the design planning and research-driven prioritizations to merge three front-end platforms, resulting in an overall higher converting product with lower tech and design debt.

# **Director of Design for Udemy**

2014-2016

- Established the discipline of design by defining and implementing key principles and practices; evolved as the company grew from 50 employees to over 200.
- Instituted processes for the collaboration, review, and knowledge sharing across multiple organization levels that created an environment for transparency, mentorship, and growth.
- Established the patterns, frameworks, and elements for brand and product, creating guidelines to enable quality production at speed.

# **Design Director for Yahoo Communications**

2013-2014

- Led the large scale, front-end redesign of Mail and Calendar for an audience of 300 million customers.
- Transformed the team's culture, tools, and the working models, increasing performance for the existing team while hiring and expanding the span of control for the group.
- Strengthened the cross-discipline team via models that inspired deep thinking, ideation, efficiency, and strategic alignment.
- Worked across the Yahoo network to define hiring practices, charters, and review criteria to ensure the quality of design.

# Design Director for Yahoo Commerce

2010-2013

- Led the development of lead-generation opportunities by focusing on meaningful values, increasing page views and time spent 30-50% across the portfolio.
- Built a multi-disciplinary team of eight teammates within four months;
  expanded portfolio to take on additional business lines.
- Reimagined the commerce portfolio, producing a forward-looking vision that informed the organization's strategy.

## VP, User Experience for Publicis Modem

PayPal, LG, UBS, SunPower Foundation 2008–2010

- Oversaw the re-launches of PayPal's consumer and business sites, bringing double-digit growth in lead generation and adoption.
- Supported LG Mobile's digital strategy by delivering rich-presence marketing experiences for all new phone releases.
- Recruited and managed team of designers; directed utilization and billable percentages across teams and accounts.

## Director, User Experience for Real Branding

Disney, ABC, ESPN, Anheuser-Busch, Lipton, Red Lobster, USGA 2007–2008

- Led the joint SOAPnet/agency team through all phases of large redesign project: developing community, architecture, and content strategies.
- Grew the experience design practice by providing thought leadership, mentoring designers, and pitching new business.
- Worked with company leadership to develop processes and deliverables, defining the scoping models for client engagement.

# Earlier Positions

### Senior Designer, AKQA

Microsoft Xbox, Target, Nike, Autodesk, McDonald's

### Director of UX, Real Branding

Disney, ABC, ESPN, Anheuser-Busch, Lipton, Red Lobster, USGA

Masters Program Study Advisor, Academy of Art University

Senior User Experience Designer, McCann Worldgroup

Microsoft

Senior User Experience Designer, Eleven Inc.

The Doctors Company

### Senior IA, Tribal DDB

Clorox, Armor All, Hidden Valley, Fresh Step, NBC Universal

### Senior Experience Designer, EVB

AT&T, Wrigley, Adidas, Leapfrog

Lead Interaction Designer, Enterpulse

Albertsons

Information Architect, Grey Global Group

Oracle, Wells Fargo

Executive Producer, Epylon Corporation

Producer, Foote, Cone & Belding 3Com, Sega Dreamcast

Producer, Think New Ideas

Silicon Graphics

Designer, Printz Electronic Design Asante

### Education

### Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, RI

BFA, industrial design, with emphasis on human/machine interfaces

### University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Liberal arts, with emphasis on economic and political sciences